ADELLE K. HOUSKER

79 Hudson Street, Apt 3 · Boston, MA 02111 · C: (507) 450-9707 · housker@gmail.com

Enthusiastic graduate of Master of Arts in Human Resources and Industrial Relations with experience in full lifecycle recruiting and knowledge of case law as it applies to labor and employee relations. Flexible, selfmotivated, and able to exercise discretion with minimal supervision as part of a team.

EDUCATION

CARLSON SCHOOL OF MANAGEMENT, U OF MN, Minneapolis, MN

2010-2012

Master of Arts in **Human Resources and Industrial Relations**

Graduate Society of Human Resources Leaders (GSHRL) student organizer

Teaching Assistantship for Labor Relations and Collective Bargaining course in HRIR Department.

CARLETON COLLEGE, Northfield, MN

2006-2010

Bachelor of Arts in Psychology

Cambridge University, UK scholarship for semester study abroad – Finance/Economics.

Cum Laude.

EXPERIENCE

WHOLE FOODS, Minnetonka, MN; South End Boston, MA

May 2015-Present

Customer Service Team Member

- Earned Employee of the Month for consistently placing first in number of funds raised for philanthropic projects, doing so by informing and engaging customers.
- Health and Safety Advisory Committee Provided leadership with action items as department's point of contact. Implemented initiative to keep café cleaner and greener by reallocating division of labor.

ROBERT HALF, Minneapolis, MN

Sept 2014-May 2015

A recruiting agency serving greater Minneapolis and St. Paul in financial services and retail industries **Contract Recruiter**

- Managed organizational development and a full lifecycle hiring process sourcing, screening, recruitment, and selection – under strict deadlines with confidentiality and professionalism.
- Assembled high performance teams from colleges, employee referrals, personal sourcing, and job fairs to build diverse talent pool in compliance with equal employment opportunity for classes protected under Title VII.
- Coordinated schedules and prepared candidate files so that managers gave fair and efficient interviews.
- Throughout audit, eased process of completing on-boarding paperwork, utilizing applicant tracking software PeopleSoft/Transcend (records and marketing), iCIMS (recruiting), Natural Insight (personnel), and First Advantage (background check).

DATA RECOGNITION CORPORATION, Plymouth, MN

Mar 2014-Aug 2014

An educational market research organization serving school districts across the nation

Team Lead

 Edited and proofread student essays. Conducted needs analysis and interpreted daily performance metrics for vendor of large-scale, content-aligned research and educational test development.

PETERSON SALT, Hopkins, MN

Mar 2013-Oct 2013

A supplier and distributor of salt products to supermarkets/industrial manufacturing for the upper Mid-west Office Manager

- Managed employees and provided office manager support to family-run business.
- Duties included employee relations work, travel logistics, calendars, invoices, collections, and accounts receivable through Sage 50 accounting software and Microsoft Office (Outlook, Word, Excel).

NATIONAL ENGINEERING RESOURCES, Brooklyn Park, MN

Jan 2012-July 2012

A professional recruiting and contract placement company serving labs and worksites nationwide.

Technical Recruiter

- Performed full lifecycle hiring process for staffing agency specializing in the placement of
 contract engineers and technicians; researched technical qualifications and market conditions,
 searched and screened resumes, conducted interviews, performed reference checks, gave
 candidate skills assessments, calculated fair margin for salary negotiations, and prepared letters
 of acceptance, declines, and other official communications. Protected proprietary and
 confidential information.
- Prepared job descriptions and posted to Internet job boards (Monster, ZipRecruiter) and social media sites (Wordpress, LinkedIn, Facebook).
- Note: this was a full-time appointment held while pursuing a master's degree full-time. Commission was earned for exceeding departmental and company objectives.

CITY OF ST. PAUL, St. Paul, MN

June 2011-Sept 2011

Labor Relations Intern

• Researched case law for NLRB arbitrations, and solicited area contracts to streamline negotiations, conflict management, and mediation.

COMMUNITY ENGAGEMENT, Minneapolis, MN; Boston, MA

Ongoing

Volunteer

- Graduate Volunteer Consultants Designed revised hiring procedures for student-run clinic offering free health care services to community to streamline overall selection process and ensure consistency and legal defensibility. Prepared presentation graphics with Adobe Photoshop.
- Raising a Reader prepare promotional materials for early education literacy outreach.
- WGBH give students, faculty, and informed electorate a memorable, enjoyable experience.
- The Cedar support the operations of this grassroots music venue.
- MPR public relations, engage attendees and spread awareness of Minnesota Public Radio.
- Accountability MN help low-income residents receive full tax refund to which they are entitled.
- Twin Cities RISE! process consultation, mentor/coach participants to prevent discouragement.